Kate Hevner Mueller papers, 1909-1981 C170
Indiana University Archives
Kate Hevner Mueller papers
1909-1981
Indiana University Archives
Mueller, Kate Hevner, 1898-1984
C170
12 cubic feet
Consists of personal papers, research notes, copies of published works, class and lecture notes, and the public speaking notes of Kate Hevner Mueller. Mueller served as the Dean of Women from 1938-1949. She also taught in the Education Department, focusing on psychology and then later personnel and guidance.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Advance notice is required.
Biographical Note
Kate Hevner Mueller was born Kate Lucile Hevner on November 1, 1898 in Westmoreland, Pennsylvania. Her father was a minister and also worked for the YMCA, while her mother was a schoolteacher. She was a middle child, her sister, Edith Dell was older and her brother, George was younger. Upon graduating from Williamsport (Pennsylvania) High School in 1916, she attended Wilson College, in Chambersburg, Pennsylvania. At Wilson, her major was English, but a Psychology class sparked her interest in that discipline. After teaching mathematics at a high school for two years, she moved to New York to attend Columbia University, this time majoring in Psychology. The work of psychologist L.L. Thurstone at the University of Chicago inspired Kate Hevner to apply for a fellowship at that school to work under his direction towards a doctoral degree. Thurstone accepted her, and in 1928, she earned her doctoral degree in Psychology, with her thesis entitled, An Empirical Study of Three Psychophysical Methods. Coincidentally, John Mueller, her future husband, also earned his doctorate at the University of Chicago in 1928 (in Sociology), but the two did not meet until 3 years later.
Upon earning her doctorate, Kate Hevner accepted a position at the University of Minnesota teaching Psychology. Not only did she teach introductory courses in Psychology, but also more advanced courses in Aesthetics, a special interest of hers which would lead the University of Oregon to "borrow" her to further develop her research in the study of the Aesthetics of Art. While working in Oregon in 1931, Kate Hevner first met John Mueller, who also had an interest in Aesthetics and Art. Letters began passing between the two, with greater and greater frequency, until they were married in 1935. Immediately after the wedding, the couple moved to Bloomington, Indiana, where John Mueller had accepted an associate professorship in Sociology.
Kate Mueller taught part-time at the IU extension campus in Indianapolis until she accepted the position of Dean of Women at IU in 1938, a position she held for ten years. Even though her work in Psychology and her collaboration in the study of the Aesthetics of art with her husband continued, her new role as Dean of Women moved Kate Mueller to further explore the disciplines of Personnel and Guidance. She became a part of the National Association of Women Deans and Counsellors and editor of the NAWDC Journal throughout the 1960s. After her resignation from the Office of the Dean of Women in 1949, Kate Mueller became an associate professor in the Education department, teaching Psychology and later moving on to teaching graduate courses in Personnel and Guidance.
Throughout these years, Kate Hevner Mueller developed into a prolific writer, a noted public speaker, and an esteemed scholar in the fields of Psychology and of Personnel and Guidance. The test for measuring appreciation of music she developed with Robert Seashore in the early 1930s became a standard for many years. In addition to scores of journal articles and corroborations with her husband, Kate Hevner Mueller also wrote Educating Women for a Changing World (1954), and Student Personnel Work in Higher Education, both highly regarded. She traveled the United States and abroad to lecture and to evaluate schools in the areas of Guidance programs, and increasingly, on the subject of women and their role in society.
In 1965, John Mueller had reached the mandatory age of retirement at the University. Just two months after his retirement, however, on September 1st, 1965, John Mueller died after a brief fight with cancer. He was buried on his and Kate Mueller's thirtieth wedding anniversary. Despite the great loss she had suffered in losing both her husband and her partner in academic pursuits, Kate Mueller continued working well into the 1970s. She continued to teach at Indiana until 1969, and then teaching for a year at the University of Florida. Even after retirement, she was still highly sought as a speaker and advisor. In 1973, she finished the study that she and John Mueller had worked on intermittently for 30 years, Twenty-Seven Major American Symphony Orchestras: A History and Analysis of Their Repertoires, Seasons 1842-43 through 1969-1970. She continued pursuing her interests, spending more time travelling abroad and enjoying the rich cultural atmosphere at Indiana and in Bloomington. However, the last five years of her life were marked with illness and physical limitations on the engagement of her varied interests. Kate Hevner Mueller died August 10, 1984, five days after suffering a stroke.
Throughout her life, Kate Hevner Mueller won numerous awards and honors, both for her research and her contributions to the areas of Psychology and Personnel and Guidance.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Kate Hevner Mueller comprise 12 cubic feet and cover a span of time from her young childhood until just a few years before her death in 1984. Kate Mueller was very meticulous, she kept virtually all her correspondence and research notes, much of which is annotated to explain its importance and relevance. Most of the collection is from the 1950s and 1960s, but a great deal also exists from her childhood and college days. The papers are organized into the following series:
Biographical and Personal Material: This series is subdivided into three subseries: Clippings- Newspaper and Magazine Clippings about KHM; Childhood and Student Papers, Stories, Report Cards, and Yearbooks- Stories and poems written by KHM as a child, report cards from grade school through college, class notes from high school and college, high school and college yearbooks, which feature school pictures and articles written by KHM; General Biographical and Personal Files- Awards, financial documents, biographies, reviews of her books, her wedding announcement, contracts, college commencement announcements, resume, etc.
Memoirs and Journals: Kate Mueller began writing her memoirs, both of her private life and her professional life. Some errors exist in the manuscripts, however. Some of the dates are off by five years, and some of the order of things is a bit skewed. The journals date mainly from KHM's early teenage years through college and a brief diary (mainly of appointments and activities) from 1981.
Correspondence: Easily the largest series. Most of the letters are from the 1950s-1960s, but is fairly weighty for the other years as well. This series is separated into three categories: Correspondence with John Mueller- When they met, he lived in Oregon and she lived in Minnesota, so letters passed between them daily for a few years before they were married in 1935. Subject- These are letters which were better classified by subject rather than by correspondent because many times KHM only wrote to an individual once or at most a couple of times, or she wrote to many people about the same thing. General- This is organized in alphabetical order with the correspondent. For the most part, these people carried on a significant correspondence with KHM or it lasted over many years. Explanatory details are included on the folder and below to further identify the correspondents and the contents.
Research Notes: This is split into two subseries: Twenty-Seven Major American Symphony Orchestras: a history and analysis of their repertoires, seasons 1842-1843 through 1969-1970 - this is the book that Kate Mueller finished in 1973. Her notes for the book are numerous enough to warrant this separate subseries. The folders do not really have a consistent or adequate labeling system, but rather than take the chance on misrepresenting the contents, the original names have been retained, but have been organized into headings such as CHARTS and NATIONALITIES below to give some organization to the multiplicity of naming methods. General Research Notes- These are all her other notes which do not pertain to the book or to class work. These folders are organized alphabetically by subject.
Teaching/Class notes: Kate Hevner Mueller kept a great deal of her class materials. They are organized into these subseries: Subject- These are notes taken or collected by KHM for use in her classes. Classes- This subseries is organized by the names/numbers of the individual classes that KHM taught and contains the materials she used for that particular class, including syllabi, assignments, and final examinations. Student Work- These folders contain work submitted by students of KHM, some dated, some undated.
Professional Organizations: Kate Mueller was involved with many organizations and because of her expertise in many disciplines, she was used professionally a great deal. The material found in this series has to do with her professional activities both within groups and as an individual scholar.
Writings: This is subcategorized into the following subseries: Speeches/Radio Addresses- typescripts of speeches, outlines, and transcripts for public speaking. Reviews- Kate Mueller reviewed many books and articles in both Psychology and Guidance and Counselling. Also included are reviews about works written by Mueller. Published Works- These are articles, monographs, and drafts for books. Included are both edited drafts and final copies, in addition to the publication themselves in some cases. Other writings and books- This contains unidentified writings by KHM, or otherwise unclassified drafts. Also contained here are the editions of books she either wrote or contributed to in some way. Not all the books she wrote are included here.
Miscellaneous materials: These materials were added to the collection after it had been processed and can all be found in Box 12. It primarily consists of record albums used in Kate and John's research. Also included are microfilm of sheet music and data taken during their research.
Arrangement
Organized into seven series: Biographical and personal material, Memoirs and journals, Correspondence, Research notes, Teaching/class notes, Professional organizations, and Writings.
Separated Material
Photographs transferred to the Archives Photographs Collection (1 flat box, 1 rc and 1 loose album).
Related Material
For the records from Mueller's tenure as Dean of Women, see Collection C165.
For the papers of Mueller's husband, John H. Mueller, see Collection C141.
Acquisition Information
Accessions 0986, 9045-9047, 9072, 2011/083.
Teacher educators --Indiana --Bloomington.; Teacher educators --Indiana --Bloomington --Biography.; Teacher educators --Indiana --Bloomington --Archives.; Teacher educators --Indiana --Bloomington --Correspondence.; Indiana University. Educational Leadership and Policy Studies Department -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Mueller, Kate Hevner, 1898-1984; Mueller, Kate Hevner, 1898-1984 -- Archives; Mueller, Kate Hevner, 1898-1984 -- Correspondence
- Biographical, Personal Material, early 1900s-1970s
  - Clippings, 1920s-1970s (Box 1)
    - Newspaper/Magazine Clippings, 1920s-1970s (Box 1)
    - Magazine Articles, 1938-1939 (Box 1)
    - Newspaper/Magazine Clippings, 1940s-1970s (Box 1)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1950s; 1970s (Box 1)
    - Newspaper/Magazine Clippings, 1950s-1960s; 1980 (Box 1)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1955; 1977 (Box 1)
  - Childhood and Student Papers, Stories, Report Cards, and Yearbooks, 1911-1927
    - Report Cards, 1909-1927 (Box 1)
    - Xeroxed High School picture, ca. 1916 (Box 1)
    - High School Publications, ca. 1916 (Box 1)
    - Original Stories and Copies of Favorite Poems, early 1900s (Box 1)
    - Notebook of Stories and Poems, 1911-1913 (Box 1)
    - Notebook of Poems and Drawings, 1912-1916 (Box 1)
    - "Things I like to reread", ca. 1918 (Box 1)
    - Original Story, 1923 (Box 1)
    - High School English Notebook with Pictures, 1914-1915 (Box 1)
    - High School English Notebook, 1915-1916 (Box 1)
    - History Class Notes and Assignments, 1916 and later (Box 1)
    - High School Science Notes and Assignments, 1916 (Box 1)
    - College Physiology Notes, 1916 (Box 1)
    - Various Class Notes and Assignments, 1916-1917 (Box 1)
    - Bible Class Notes and Assignments, 1917-1918 (Box 1)
    - Biology Class Notes, 1917-1918 (Box 1)
    - French Class Notes and Assignments, 1917 (Box 1)
    - English Class Notes, ca. 1917 (Box 1)
    - Bible Class Notes, 1918 (Box 1)
    - College Calendars and yearbooks, 1918-1926 (Box 1)
    - English Class Notes and Assignments, ca. 1918 (Box 1)
    - A Study of Thurstone Test IV Given to Five Classes at Wilson College, ca. 1919 (Box 1)
    - Art History Class Notebook, ca. 1919 (Box 1)
    - Essay on Thurstone's Test (with her comments and teachers?), ca. 1919 (Box 1)
    - Psychology I, ca. 1919 (Box 1)
    - Philosophy III, ca. 1919 (Box 1)
    - Stories and English Assignments, ca. 1919 (Box 1)
    - Education Class Notes, 1920 (Box 1)
    - English Class Notes, ca. 1920 (Box 1)
    - Various Notes from College, 1920-1927 (Box 1)
    - Aesthetics Courses, 1924-1927 (Box 1)
    - Scaling Problem (draft), 1927 (Box 1)
    - Weber's Law (draft), undated (Box 1)
  - General Biographical and Personal Files, 1922-1977
    - Awards, Honors, Degrees, Certificates, 1922-1978 (Box 1)
    - Financial Records, ca. 1924 (Box 1)
    - Commencement Announcement University of Chicago, 1928 (Box 1)
    - Music (for appreciation tests?) Department of Psychology University of Minnesota, ca. 1928-1935 (Box 1)
    - Wedding Announcement, 1935 (Box 1)
    - Financial Records, 1950's-1980's (Box 1)
    - Contracts, 1952; 1959; undated (Box 1)
    - Wilson College 35th Reunion, 1955 (Box 1)
    - Application for Sabbatical Leave, 1966 (Box 1)
    - Resume, 1969 (Box 1)
    - Brief Biography and Family History, undated (Box 1)
    - Personal Keepsakes (membership cards, poems written for the Muellers, miscellaneous), 1928-1965 (Box 1)
    - Royalty Statements, 1962-1977 (Box 1)
- Memoirs and Journals, 1911-1981
  - Diaries/Journals, 1911-1981 (Box 2)
    - "Diary Kept 1911-12-13", 1911-1913 (Box 2)
    - "Diary Kept at Elkland Summer 1914" (Box 2)
    - "Diary Winter 1915-1916" (Box 2)
    - Various Writings (stories, personal notes), ca. 1920s (Box 2)
    - Various Journal Entries, 1925-1928 (Box 2)
    - Diary, ca. late 1920s (Box 2)
    - Diary, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Memoirs, 1969-1970s
    - "Memoirs of Kate Hevner Mueller", ca. 1976 (Box 2)
    - Memoirs 1935-1971, ca. 1970s (Box 2)
    - Memoirs 1937-1949, ca. 1970s (Box 2)
    - Career Memories, ca. 1969 (Box 2)
  - Travel Journals, 1933-1977
    - Italy, Germany, 1933 (Box 2)
    - Germany Trip, 1951 (Box 2)
    - Europe, 1963 (Box 2)
    - European Trip, 1964 (Box 2)
    - Travel Journals and Memoirs, 1964-1977 (Box 2)
    - France, 1966 (Box 2)
    - India, ca. 1970s (Box 2)
    - Asia, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Scandinavia, 1972 (Box 2)
    - New York, 1975 (Box 2)
    - South Pacific, 1975 (Box 2)
- Correspondence, 1909-1979
  - John H. Mueller Correspondence, 1931-1960
    - Jun 1931- Sep 1932 (Box 2)
    - Oct 1932-Dec 1932 (Box 2)
    - Jan-Mar 1933 (Box 2)
    - Apr-Jun 1933 (Box 2)
    - Jul-Dec 1933 (Box 2)
    - Jan-Jul 1934 (Box 2)
    - 1945-1960 (Box 2)
    - Sep-Nov 1955 (Box 2)
  - Subject Correspondence, 1927-1979
    - Academic Courses - IU, 1949-1961 (Box 2)
    - Academics to/from students, 1931-1965; 1952-1956 (Box 2)
    - Aesthetics, 1949-1952 (Box 2)
      - -Psychological Associations (Box 2)
      - -Regarding publications (Box 2)
    - American Association of University Women (AAUW), 1954-1978 (Box 2)
    - American board of Examiners in Professional Psychology, 1956 (Box 2)
    - American Council on Education -Advisory Service on Student Personnel Work, 1947-1950 (Box 2)
    - American Personnel and Guidance Association, 1962-1966 (Box 2)
    - American Psychological Association, 1935-1973 (Box 2)
    - American Symphony Orchestra League, 1968-1970 (Box 2)
    - Art Appreciation (analysis, methods), 1930-1935 (Box 2)
    - Association for Higher Education, 1961-1966 (Box 2)
    - Business Transactions, 1941-1959 (Box 2)
    - Classmates, 1927-1976 (Box 2)
    - College Evaluation /Recommendations, Workshops for counselling/personnel, 1949-1969 (Box 2)
    - College Student Personnel Institute, 1964-1966 (Box 2)
    - Congratulations, Thank Yous, and Invitations - (Box 2)
      - General, 1929-1974 (Box 2)
      - Professional, 1931-1979 (Box 2)
    - Dean of Women, 1938-1948 (Box 2)
    - Delta Kappa Gamma Society Award, 1956 (Box 2)
    - Educating Women for a Changing World (Box 3)
      - University of Minnesota Press, 1950-1968 (Box 3)
      - -General, 1949-1956 (Box 3)
    - Educating Women for a Changing World (Box 3)
    - Financial (Box 3)
      - 1965-1973 (Box 3)
      - -Fellowships, Salaries, 1925-1935 (Box 3)
    - Florida State University, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
    - General Correspondence - Personal, 1935-1975 (Box 3)
    - Hosting German Women, 1949 (Box 3)
    - Inquiries - General, 1937-1977 (Box 3)
    - Job Inquiries, Notices, 1926-1937 (Box 3)
    - Karsten Visit (from Germany), 1955 (Box 3)
    - Lectures (Box 3)
      - - Guidance and Personnel, 1947-1968 (Box 3)
      - - Women, 1951-1968 (Box 3)
      - - Other, 1961-1964 (Box 3)
    - Legal (Mainly dealing with the death of John Mueller), 1965-1968 (Box 3)
    - Letters from KHM to many recipients, 1960-1978 (Box 3)
    - Medical, 1974; 1980 (Box 3)
    - Music, Music Appreciation, 1931-1969 (Box 3)
    - Music Appreciation Test (Box 3)
      - -Inquiries and Comments, 1931-1976 (Box 3)
      - -Stoelting Co., Publisher, 1934-1949 (Box 3)
    - Music Teachers National Association, 1935; 1938 (Box 3)
    - National Association of Student Personnel Administrators (NASPA), 1966; 1978 (Box 3)
    - National Association of Women Deans and Counselors (NAWDC), 1953-1959 (Box 3)
    - NAWDC (mostly dealing with the Journal) (Box 3)
      - 1960 (Box 3)
      - 1961-1962 (Box 3)
      - 1963 (Box 3)
      - 1964 (Box 3)
      - 1965 (Box 3)
      - 1966 (Box 3)
      - 1967 (Box 3)
      - 1968 (Box 3)
      - 1969 (Box 3)
      - 1970-1974 (Box 3)
    - Older Women Project, 1963-1966 (Box 3)
    - Orchestra Project - (Box 3)
      - Computers, 1968-1972 (Box 3)
      - General, 1967-1974 (Box 3)
      - IU Press/Foundation Publications, 1971-1977 (Box 3)
      - Preparation, 1967-1971 (Box 3)
      - Rockefeller Foundation, 1967-1976 (Box 3)
    - Outline of Psychology -Longmans, Green and Co. Publishers, 1934-1935 (Box 3)
    - Personnel and Guidance Journal, 1955; 1957 (Box 3)
    - Personnel Work in Higher Education -Houghton Mifflin, Publishers, 1959-1971 (Box 3)
    - Phi Beta Kappa, 1950 (Box 3)
    - Presidential Campaigns -Scholars for Nixon and Lodge, 1960 (Box 3)
    - Professional Correspondence (Box 3)
      - -Various, 1936-1975 (Box 3)
      - -IU, 1938-1975 (Box 3)
    - Professional Organizations -Various, 1938-1974 (Box 3)
    - Publications, 1929-1968 (Box 4)
    - Publications - Reviews and Critiques of Works by Other Authors, 1947-1972 (Box 4)
    - Recommendations, 1936-1972 (Box 4)
    - Requests for Quotation Permission, 1938-1967 (Box 4)
    - Student Development in Small Colleges - Project, 1968 (Box 4)
    - Sympathy Cards, Notes, etc. - on the death of John Mueller, 1965 (Box 4)
    - Television Show on CBS About Women, 1959 (Box 4)
    - Travel (Box 4)
      - - European Trip, 1966 (Box 4)
      - - Orient, 1971 (Box 4)
      - - European Trip, 1972 (Box 4)
      - - Cruise on Queen Elizabeth II, 1976 (Box 4)
    - Twenty-Seven Major American Symphony Orchestras: a history and analysis of their repertoires, seasons 1842-1843 through 1969-1970 (Box 4)
      - -Comments, corrections, 1974 (Box 4)
      - -Requests for information, directions for researchers, 1970; 1974 (Box 4)
    - Thesis (Doctoral)-Clark University Press, Publishers, 1928-1930 (Box 4)
    - Women, 1949-1959 (Box 4)
  - General Correspondence, 1909-1979
    - Arnheim, Rudolf, 1953-1957 (Box 4)
    - Benns, F. Lee and Jessie, 1950-1967 (Box 4)
    - Beck, Ruth -with NAWDC, 1954-1975 (Box 4)
    - Bonny, Helen, 1973-1975 (Box 4)
    - Brendel, Maria, 1950-1957 (Box 4)
    - Bryan, William Lowe, 1954 (Box 4)
    - Calia, Vincent, 1965-1971 (Box 4)
    - Catton, Barbara -with NAWDC, 1953-1964 (Box 4)
    - Carr, Harvey -teacher at University of Chicago, 1927-1938 (Box 4)
    - Chambers, M.M. -Dept. of Educational Administration Illinois State University, 1973-1978 (Box 4)
    - Cowley, W. H. -Stanford University, 1963-1964 (Box 4)
    - Crane, Esther, 1937-1970 (Box 4)
    - Davidson (Pattillo), Ann, 1969-1975 (Box 4)
    - Davis, Jo and Merrill, 1953-1971 (Box 4)
    - Deppen, Margaret -Dean of Women, Ohio University, 1961-1964 (Box 4)
    - Disert, Margaret -Dean of Women, Wilson College, 1939-1971 (Box 4)
    - Donovan, Eleanor "Eleanor PD" -Cousin of KHM, 1915-1965 (Box 4)
    - Eberle, Ann, 1970-1972 (Box 4)
    - Elliott, R.M. "Mike" -University of Minnesota Department of Psychology, 1928-1940 (Box 4)
    - Evans, Gladys, 1938-1954 (Box 4)
    - Farnsworth, Paul -Stanford University, 1931-1954 (Box 4)
    - Girardot, Peter and Charles Green, 1971-1972 (Box 4)
    - Gordon, Phoebe, 1952-1955 (Box 4)
    - Griffith, Robert -Memphis State University School of Music, 1969-1975 (Box 4)
    - Handley, Harold - Governor of Indiana, 1957 (Box 4)
    - Hare, Dora, 1967; undated (Box 4)
    - Harris, Anna Rankin -NAWDC, 1962-1971 (Box 4)
    - Hart, Philip, 1970-1976 (Box 4)
    - Hart, Mary, "Miss Mary" -Former teacher, 1955-1956 (Box 4)
    - Havens, Paul Swain - President of Wilson College, 1951-1964 (Box 4)
    - Hawkes, Anna L. Rose - Dean of Students, Mills College, California, 1950; 1958 (Box 4)
    - Heidbreder, Edna, 1938-1974 (Box 4)
    - Hevner, Martha, Joie May -Sister-in-law and niece of KHM, 1945-1970 (Box 4)
    - Hevner, Winnbert and Joie -Parents of KHM, 1909-1940s (Box 4)
    - Hilton, Eunice, 1955-1967 (Box 4)
    - Hornyak, R. Robert, 1966-1967 (Box 4)
    - Hughes, Alice, 1954 (Box 4)
    - Johnson (Norville), Harriett (Box 4)
      - Trip to Europe, 1966 (Box 4)
      - Trip, 1972 (Box 4)
      - 1930-1973 (Box 4)
      - 1957-1964 (Box 4)
    - Kerr, Margaret -Classmate from Wilson College, 1970-1971 (Box 4)
    - Kirkbrite, Virginia -Taught for KHM in the summer, 1960-1967 (Box 4)
    - Kneisel, Pamela, 1976 (Box 4)
    - Laurent, Robert and MiMi, 1954-1957 (Box 4)
    - Lloyd-Jones, Esther -Director of Guidance, Columbia Univeristy, 1935-1967 (Box 4)
    - MacClintock, Lander and Carol, 1954-1969 (Box 4)
    - Mendel, Hansi, 1973 (Box 4)
    - Mitchell, Georgianna -husband, Allan; daughter Georgianna (Alice); son-in-law Lew Rivlin, 1955-1967 (Box 4)
    - Mueller, Phoebe, George -also includes other Muellers, 1932-1960s (Box 4)
    - Myers, Florence, 1962-1975 (Box 4)
    - Nelson, Leona, 1945-1965 (Box 4)
    - Nichol, Gilbert, 1962-1965 (Box 4)
    - Nixon, Richard -Including secretaries, 1960-1961 (Box 4)
    - O'Donnell, Bruce, 1966-1967 (Box 4)
    - Orvis, Mary, 1937-1954 (Box 4)
    - Park, Eldon, 1962-1979 (Box 4)
    - Pattillo, N.A. -President, Randloph-Macon Women's College, 1932-1933 (Box 4)
    - Phillips, Florence "Flossie" -Dean of Women, Texas Tech, 1961-1967 (Box 4)
    - Rachal, Patricia, 1970 (Box 5)
    - Rigg, Melvin -Director of Personnel, Highlands University, New Mexico, 1936-1955 (Box 5)